Ever wondered about the differences between AI, ML, DL and
ds? Well, we're about to explore all of those today. Stay tuned.
So let's dive right into it. So AI versus ML versus
DL versus DS, a whole bunch of jargon, but we're going to clarify
all of that right up. So let's kick things off and take a look at
AI. So AI is really to do with
the ability of computers and machines to perform tasks without explicitly
programming them, otherwise known as the ability for computers
and machines to think by themselves. So we typically
break out AI into two key categories. These are general AI
and narrow AI. General AI typically refers to the ability
for a computer or a machine to be able to handle a wide variety of
tasks. Us as humans have the ability to do a whole heap
of stuff. We can see, we can speak, we can hear, we can read,
we can drive, we can do a whole range of things. The ability for AI
and machines to be able to do a broad range of tasks similar to humans
is what we typically refer to as general AI.
Now, we're still a little bit of a while away from true general AI,
but that's not to say it's not to come. Now,
narrow AI, on the other hand, is the ability for a machine to handle a
really simple or a really narrow range of tasks. So that could possibly be the
ability to translate speech to text, or to classify images as having
different categories, or the ability to predict house prices, for example.
All of these are examples of narrow AI. So I'm going
to be painting a bunch of visual imagery to help you remember some of these
topics. So the first one, in terms of breaking out general and narrow
AI, or the ability to remember general and narrow AI,
is just picture a really narrow or really skinny general in your mind.
So that way you know that there's two different types of AI, general and narrow.
Now onto the next topic, machine learning. So we've taken a look at AI as
being broken up into general and narrow. But how does machine learning fit into this?
Well, machine learning is the application of narrow AI
to specific tasks. Now, when we typically talk about machine learning,
we often compare it to traditional programming. So in traditional programming,
we supply data plus rules or conditional logic, and we get answers.
Now, in machine learning, on the other hand, we provide data plus historical
answers to get rules. We can then pass new data to get new answers.
So this is a bit of a change in the paradigm of how computer scientists
and machine learning engineers are building programs these days.
So what are some typical machine learning tasks? Well,
we broadly break out machine learning into three key categories.
These are supervised learning, unsupervised learning, and semisupervised
learning. So let's take a look at supervised learning first. So,
supervised learning can be broadly broken out into two key categories.
These are classification and regression. Classification is all
to do with grouping things into categories or labels.
So say you had a big data set on all the different types of pizzas
you've liked and whether or not you've liked them. Yes or no,
you could take that data and pass it through to a classification algorithm
to help it learn which types of pizzas you like. So then when you pass
through a new list of ingredients, it would be able to predict, yes, you would
like that pizza or no, you might not. Regression, on the
other hand, is all to do with predicting continuous variables. Some great
examples of regression are sales forecasting and predicting prices
of houses. So that encapsulates supervised learning. Now, what about unsupervised
learning? Well, there's two key things to think about when you think
of unsupervised learning. These are really clustering. So the ability to
group people together. So say you wanted to group together high performing and low performing
and medium performing employees, or high value, low value,
medium value customers, or a whole bunch of other different types of data.
But really it's all to do with grouping things together. Now, dimensionality reduction,
on the other hand, is all to do with condensing the features that
you've got within a machine learning model. So a lot of the time you might
start out with a huge data set with a lot of columns, and you're not
really sure which of those columns are important for your machine learning model,
dimensionality reduction helps you reduce the number of columns
that you've got so that you can really focus on the important ones.
Now, in order to remember supervised learning and unsupervised
learning, I'd suggest you remember this initialism, Christopher Robin
caught a duck. So that way you remember classification,
regression, clustering and dimensionality reduction. So that
takes care of supervised and unsupervised learning. But what about semi supervised
learning? Well, this is where reinforcement learning comes in.
Now, reinforcement learning has four key things. These are
an agent, an action, an environment, and a reward.
It's similar to how you might choose to condition a dog. A dog
might do something right, and you might reward it with a piece of food.
In a similar way, we train reinforcement learning models to act in a
correct way in a given environment in order to learn appropriate actions given
that specific environment. Now, the best way to remember,
reinforcement learning techniques is to remember area 51.
So that way you remember agent reward environment and actions.
Okay? So that takes care of machine learning. Now we're going to delve a little
bit deeper and get into deep learning. So deep learning is a
subset of machine learning, and really it's to do with performing machine
learning tasks using deep neural networks.
Now, deep neural networks are networks that have multiple hidden
layers. So if you've ever seen a diagram that looks sort of
like this, this is a representation of a neural network.
But specifically in this case, this is a deep neural network because
it has multiple hidden layers. Now, the best way to remember
deep learning is to remember that deep learning is just like an onion. It has
multiple layers, little bit like Shrek. Now, that sort of covers
AI, ML and DL. What about data science?
Well, data science is the practice that sits over AI,
ML and DL. It basically is the art of
extracting knowledge, insight and meaning from data. The best way to
remember the key components of data science are to look at the crisp DM
framework. So the crisp DM framework stands for the cross
industry standard process for data mining. And basically it's a framework to
help you along your way to producing really good data science
projects. Now, there's six key steps in the data
science process. These are business understanding. So understanding
the business that you're working with and the environment in which they operate.
Two data understanding. So understanding the data that
you've got on hand. So whether or not you've got missing values,
visualizing that data and taking a look at some summary statistics,
we've then got data preparation. So this is all to do with getting our
data ready for modeling. In this step, we might perform some feature engineering
and create some new columns. We might fill in some missing values and a whole
bunch of other data preparation steps, like, for example, splitting our
data into training and testing. Next, we've got my favorite,
which is modeling. This is all to do with training your machine learning algorithms
to perform well on a specific task. Once we've trained our
models in that modeling step, we get onto evaluation.
Given that we've trained our model, we want to make sure that it's going to
work well once we deploy it into the real world. This is what the evaluation
step is all about. In this step, we try to check whether or not
our model is likely to perform well using specific evaluation
metrics. Now, once we've gone through all of that, the last step is
to go and deploy our model. In order to deploy our model, we could release
it as a rest API containerize it up or save it as
a binary so we can go and use it elsewhere. Now,
a great way to remember Chris DM is to remember Barry drove directly to
the medical emergency department. That way you remember business understanding
data understanding data preparation, modeling, evaluation,
and deployment. Now, I've talked a lot about theory, but where do the python
packages that you typically see used fit into this framework?
Well, in terms of data science, numpy, pandas, and Matplotlib
are probably going to be the most important packages that you see floating around.
Numpy and pandas help you traverse and explore your data and
really work with your data in terms of performing manipulations and
data preparation. Matplotlib and Seaborne help you visualize
that data and explore it even further. Now, the most important
library in terms of machine learning is probably scikitlearn. So Scikitlearn's
been around for quite some time and gives you a whole bunch of
really powerful algorithms and utilities to help use them
to train your machine learning models. Now, deep learning is becoming increasingly
popular, and there's a large number of libraries that can help you perform
deep learning. Some of which are notable are tensorflow,
Keras, Pytorch, and piano, just to name a few. And that
about wraps up AI versus ML versus DL vs.
Ds. Thanks so much for tuning in, guys. Hopefully you found this video useful.
If you did, be sure to give it a thumbs up and hit subscribe.
Until next time.
Ever wondered about the differences between AI, ML,
DL and ds? Well, we're about to explore all of those today.
Stay tuned. So let's dive right into it. So AI versus ML versus
DL versus DS, a whole bunch of jargon, but we're going to clarify
all of that right up. So let's kick things off and take a look at
AI. So AI is really to
do with the ability of computers and machines to perform tasks
without explicitly programming them, otherwise known as the
ability for computers and machines to think by themselves. So we
typically break out AI into two key categories. These are general
AI and narrow AI. General AI typically refers to
the ability for a computer or a machine to be able to handle a wide
variety of tasks. Us as humans have the ability to do
a whole heap of stuff. We can see, we can speak, we can hear,
we can read, we can drive, we can do a whole range of things.
The ability for AI and machines to be able to do a broad range
of tasks similar to humans is what we typically refer to as general
AI. Now, we're still a little bit of a while away from true
general AI, but that's not to say it's not to come.
Now, narrow AI, on the other hand, is the ability for a machine
to handle a really simple or a really narrow range of tasks.
So that could possibly be the ability to translate speech to text,
or to classify images as having different categories, or the ability
to predict house prices, for example. All of these are examples
of narrow AI. So I'm going to be painting a bunch of
visual imagery to help you remember some of these topics. So the first one,
in terms of breaking out general and narrow AI, or the ability to
remember general and narrow AI, is just picture a really narrow
or really skinny general in your mind. So that way you know that there's two
different types of AI, general and narrow. Now onto the next topic,
machine learning. So we've taken a look at AI as being broken up into general
and narrow. But how does machine learning fit into this? Well,
machine learning is the application of narrow AI to specific tasks.
Now, when we typically talk about machine learning, we often compare it to traditional
programming. So in traditional programming, we supply data plus rules
or conditional logic, and we get answers. Now, in machine
learning, on the other hand, we provide data plus historical
answers to get rules. We can then pass new data to get new
answers. So this is a bit of a change in the paradigm of how computer
scientists and machine learning engineers are building programs these days.
So what are some typical machine learning tasks? Well, we broadly
break out machine learning into three key categories.
These are supervised learning, unsupervised learning, and semisupervised
learning. So let's take a look at supervised learning first. So, supervised learning can be
broadly broken out into two key categories. These are
classification and regression. Classification is all to do with
grouping things into categories or labels. So say you had
a big data set on all the different types of pizzas you've liked
and whether or not you've liked them. Yes or no, you could take
that data and pass it through to a classification algorithm
to help it learn which types of pizzas you like. So then when you pass
through a new list of ingredients, it would be able to predict, yes, you would
like that pizza or no, you might not. Regression, on the other
hand, is all to do with predicting continuous variables. Some great examples
of regression are sales forecasting and predicting prices of houses.
So that encapsulates supervised learning. Now, what about unsupervised
learning? Well, there's two key things to think about when you think of
unsupervised learning. These are really clustering. So the ability
to group people together. So say you wanted to group together high performing and
low performing and medium performing employees, or high value,
low value, medium value customers, or a whole bunch of other different types of
data. But really it's all to do with grouping things together.
Now, dimensionality reduction, on the other hand, is all to do with condensing
the features that you've got within a machine learning model. So a lot of the
time you might start out with a huge data set with a lot of columns,
and you're not really sure which of those columns are important for your machine learning
model, dimensionality reduction helps you reduce the number
of columns that you've got so that you can really focus on the important
ones. Now, in order to remember supervised learning and
unsupervised learning, I'd suggest you remember this initialism,
Christopher Robin caught a duck. So that way you remember classification,
regression, clustering and dimensionality reduction. So that
takes care of supervised and unsupervised learning. But what about semi
supervised learning? Well, this is where reinforcement learning comes
in. Now, reinforcement learning has four key things. These are
an agent, an action, an environment, and a reward.
It's similar to how you might choose to condition a dog. A dog
might do something right, and you might reward it with a piece of food.
In a similar way, we train reinforcement learning models to act
in a correct way in a given environment in order to learn appropriate
actions given that specific environment. Now, the best way
to remember, reinforcement learning techniques is to remember area
51. So that way you remember agent reward environment
and actions. Okay? So that takes care of machine learning. Now we're going
to delve a little bit deeper and get into deep learning. So deep
learning is a subset of machine learning, and really it's to do with performing
machine learning tasks using deep neural networks.
Now, deep neural networks are networks that have multiple hidden layers.
So if you've ever seen a diagram that looks sort of like this,
this is a representation of a neural network.
But specifically in this case, this is a deep neural network because
it has multiple hidden layers. Now, the best way to remember deep
learning is to remember that deep learning is just like an onion.
It has multiple layers, little bit like Shrek. Now, that sort
of covers AI, ML and DL. What about data science?
Well, data science is the practice that sits over AI,
ML and DL. It basically is the art
of extracting knowledge, insight and meaning from data.
The best way to remember the key components of data science are to look at
the crisp DM framework. So the crisp DM framework stands for
the cross industry standard process for data mining. And basically it's
a framework to help you along your way to producing really good data
science projects. Now, there's six key steps in the data
science process. These are business understanding. So understanding
the business that you're working with and the environment in which they operate.
Two data understanding. So understanding the data that
you've got on hand. So whether or not you've got missing values,
visualizing that data and taking a look at some summary statistics,
we've then got data preparation. So this is all to do with getting
our data ready for modeling. In this step, we might perform some feature engineering
and create some new columns. We might fill in some missing values and a whole
bunch of other data preparation steps, like, for example, splitting our
data into training and testing. Next, we've got my favorite, which is modeling.
This is all to do with training your machine learning algorithms to perform
well on a specific task. Once we've trained our models in
that modeling step, we get onto evaluation. Given that we've trained
our model, we want to make sure that it's going to work well once we
deploy it into the real world. This is what the evaluation step is
all about. In this step, we try to check whether or not our model is
likely to perform well using specific evaluation metrics.
Now, once we've gone through all of that, the last step is to go and
deploy our model. In order to deploy our model, we could release it as a
rest API containerize it up or save it as a binary so
we can go and use it elsewhere. Now, a great way to remember
Chris DM is to remember Barry drove directly to the medical
emergency department. That way you remember business understanding data
understanding data preparation, modeling, evaluation,
and deployment. Now, I've talked a lot about theory, but where do the
python packages that you typically see used fit into this framework?
Well, in terms of data science, numpy, pandas, and Matplotlib are
probably going to be the most important packages that you see floating around.
Numpy and pandas help you traverse and explore your data and really
work with your data in terms of performing manipulations and data preparation.
Matplotlib and Seaborne help you visualize that data and explore
it even further. Now, the most important library in terms of machine learning is
probably scikitlearn. So Scikitlearn's been around for quite some time
and gives you a whole bunch of really powerful algorithms
and utilities to help use them to train your machine learning models.
Now, deep learning is becoming increasingly popular, and there's a
large number of libraries that can help you perform deep learning.
Some of which are notable are tensorflow, Keras,
Pytorch, and piano, just to name a few. And that
about wraps up AI versus ML versus DL vs.
Ds. Thanks so much for tuning in, guys. Hopefully you found this video useful.
If you did, be sure to give it a thumbs up and hit subscribe.
Until next time.