Ever wondered about the differences between AI, ML, DL and
ds? Well, we're about to explore all of those today.
Stay tuned. So let's dive right into it. So AI versus
ML versus DL versus DS, a whole bunch of jargon,
but we're going to clarify all of that right up. So let's kick
things off and take a look at AI. So AI
is really to do with the ability of computers and machines to perform tasks
without explicitly programming them, otherwise known as
the ability for computers and machines to think by themselves.
So we typically break out AI into two key categories.
These are general AI and narrow AI. General AI
typically refers to the ability for a computer or a machine to be
able to handle a wide variety of tasks. Us as humans have
the ability to do a whole heap of stuff. We can see, we can speak,
we can hear, we can read, we can drive, we can do a whole range
of things. The ability for AI and machines to be able to
do a broad range of tasks similar to humans is what we typically refer
to as general AI. Now, we're still a little bit of a while
away from true general AI, but that's not to say it's not to
come. Now, narrow AI, on the other hand, is the ability
for a machine to handle a really simple or a really narrow
range of tasks. So that could possibly be the ability to translate speech to
text, or to classify images as having different categories,
or the ability to predict house prices, for example, or all of
these are examples of narrow AI. So I'm going to be painting a
bunch of visual imagery to help you remember some of these topics. So the first
one, in terms of breaking out general and narrow AI, or the ability to
remember general and narrow AI, is just picture a really narrow
or really skinny general in your mind. So that way you know that there's two
different types of AI, general and narrow. Now onto the next topic,
machine learning. So we've taken a look at AI as being broken up into general
and narrow. But how does machine learning fit into this? Well,
machine learning is the application of narrow AI to specific tasks.
Now, when we typically talk about machine learning, we often compare it to traditional programming.
So in traditional programming, we supply data plus rules or
conditional logic, and we get answers. Now, in machine learning,
on the other hand, we provide data plus historical answers to
get rules. We can then pass new data to get new answers. So this
is a bit of a change in the paradigm of how computer scientists and
machine learning engineers are building programs these days. So what are
some typical machine learning tasks? Well, we broadly break
out machine learning into three key categories. These are
supervised learning, unsupervised learning, and semi supervised
learning. So let's take a look at supervised learning first. So, supervised learning
can be broadly broken out into two key categories. These are
classification and regression. Classification is all
to do with grouping things into categories or labels.
So say you had a big data set on all the different types of pizzas
you've liked and whether or not you've liked them. Yes or no. You could take
that data and pass it through to a classification algorithm to
help it learn which types of pizzas you like. So then when you pass through
a new list of ingredients, it would be able to predict, yes,
you would like that pizza or no, you might not. Regression, on the other
hand, is all to do with predicting continuous variables.
Some great examples of regression are sales forecasting and predicting
prices of houses. So that encapsulates supervised learning. Now, what about unsupervised
learning? Well, there's two key things to think about when you think of unsupervised
learning. These are really clustering. So the ability to group people together.
So say you wanted to group together high performing and low performing and medium
performing employees, or high value, low value, medium value customers,
or a whole bunch of other different types of data. But really it's all to
do with grouping things together. Now, dimensionality reduction, on the
other hand, is all to do with condensing the features that
you've got within a machine learning model. So a lot of the time you might
start out with a huge data set with a lot of columns, and you're not
really sure which of those columns are important for your machine learning model.
Dimensionality reduction helps you reduce the number of columns that
you've got so that you can really focus on the important ones.
Now, in order to remember supervised learning and unsupervised learning,
I'd suggest you remember this initialism, Christopher Robin caught
a duck. So that way you remember classification, regression,
clustering and dimensionality reduction. So that takes care of supervised
and unsupervised learning. But what about semi supervised learning? Well,
this is where reinforcement learning comes in. Now, reinforcement learning has four
key things. These are an agent, an action,
an environment, and a reward. It's similar to how you might choose to
condition a dog. A dog might do something right and you might reward it
with a piece of food. In a similar way, we train reinforcement
learning models to act in a correct way in a given environment in order
to learn appropriate actions given that specific environment.
Now, the best way to remember reinforcement learning techniques is to remember
area 51. So that way you remember agent reward environment
and actions. Okay? So that takes care of machine learning.
Now we're going to delve a little bit deeper and get into deep learning.
So deep learning is a subset of machine learning, and really it's to do
with performing machine learning tasks using deep neural
networks. Now, deep neural networks are networks that
have multiple hidden layers. So if you've ever seen a diagram that looks
sort of like this, this is a representation of a neural
network. But specifically in this case, this is a deep neural network
because it has multiple hidden layers. Now, the best way to remember deep
learning is to remember that deep learning is just like an onion. It has
multiple layers, a little bit like Shrek. Now, that sort of
covers AI, ML and DL. What about data science?
Well, data science is the practice that sits over
AI, ML and DL. It basically is the art
of extracting knowledge, insight and meaning from data.
The best way to remember the key components of data science are to look at
the CrispDM framework. So the CrisPDM framework
stands for the cross industry standard process for data mining. And basically
it's a framework to help you along your way to producing really
good data science projects. Now, there's six key steps
in the data science process. These are business understanding.
So understanding the business that you're working with and the environment in which they
operate. Two data understanding. So understanding the
data that you've got on hand. So whether or not you've got missing values,
visualizing that data and taking a look at some summary statistics,
we've then got data preparation. So this is all to do with getting
our data ready for modeling. In this step, we might perform some feature
engineering and create some new columns. We might fill in some missing values and,
and a whole bunch of other data preparation steps, like, for example,
splitting our data into training and testing. Next,
we've got my favorite, which is modeling. This is all to do with training your
machine learning algorithms to perform well on a specific
task. Once we've trained our models in that modeling step,
we get onto evaluation. Given that we've trained our model,
we want to make sure that it's going to work well once we deploy it
into the real world. This is what the evaluation step is all about.
In this step, we try to check whether or not our model is likely to
perform well using specific evaluation metrics. Now, once we've
gone through all of that, the last step is to go and deploy our
model. In order to deploy our model, we could release it as a rest API,
containerize it up or save it as a binary so we can go and
use it elsewhere. Now, a great way to remember CrispDM is to remember
Barry drove directly to the medical emergency department. That way
you remember business understanding data, understanding data preparation,
modeling, evaluation, and deployment. Now, I've talked a lot about theory,
but where do the python packages that you typically see used fit into
this framework? Well, in terms of data science, numpy,
pandas and Matplotlib are probably going to be the most important packages that
you see floating around. Numpy and pandas help you traverse
and explore your data and really work with your data. In terms of performing manipulations
and data preparation, Matplotlib and Seaborn help you visualize that
data and explore it even further. Now, the most important library
in terms of machine learning is probably scikit learn. So scikit learn has
been around for quite some time and gives you a whole bunch of
really powerful algorithms and utilities to help use them to train
your machine learning models. Now, deep learning is becoming increasingly
popular, and there's a large number of libraries that can help you
perform deep learning, some of which, which are notable, are tensorflow,
Keras, Pytorch, and piano, just to name a few.
And that about wraps up AI versus ML versus DL
versus ds. Thanks so much for tuning in, guys. Hopefully you found
this video useful. If you did, be sure to give it a thumbs up and
hit subscribe until next time.
Ever wondered about the differences between AI, ML,
DL and ds? Well, we're about to explore all of those
today. Stay tuned. So let's dive right into it. So AI
versus ML versus DL versus DS, a whole bunch
of jargon, but we're going to clarify all of that right up.
So let's kick things off and take a look at AI.
So AI is really to do with the ability of computers
and machines to perform tasks without explicitly programming them,
otherwise known as the ability for computers and machines to think
by themselves. So we typically break out AI into
two key categories. These are general AI and narrow
AI. General AI typically refers to the ability for
a computer or a machine to be able to handle a wide variety of
tasks. Us as humans have the ability to do a whole heap of stuff.
We can see, we can speak, we can hear, we can read, we can drive,
we can do a whole range of things. The ability for AI
and machines to be able to do a broad range of tasks similar to
humans is what we typically refer to as general AI.
Now, we're still a little bit of a while away from true general AI,
but that's not to say it's not to come. Now, narrow AI,
on the other hand, is the ability for a machine to handle a really
simple or a really narrow range of tasks. So that could possibly be the ability
to translate speech to text, or to classify images as having different
categories, or the ability to predict house prices, for example,
or all of these are examples of narrow AI. So I'm going
to be painting a bunch of visual imagery to help you remember some of these
topics. So the first one, in terms of breaking out general and narrow
AI, or the ability to remember general and narrow AI,
is just picture a really narrow or really skinny general in your mind. So that
way you know that there's two different types of AI, general and narrow.
Now onto the next topic, machine learning. So we've taken a look at AI as
being broken up into general and narrow. But how does machine learning fit into
this? Well, machine learning is the application of narrow AI to
specific tasks. Now, when we typically talk about machine learning,
we often compare it to traditional programming. So in traditional programming,
we supply data plus rules or conditional logic,
and we get answers. Now, in machine learning, on the other hand,
we provide data plus historical answers to get rules. We can
then pass new data to get new answers. So this is a bit of a
change in the paradigm of how computer scientists and machine learning engineers
are building programs these days. So what are some typical machine
learning tasks? Well, we broadly break out machine learning into three
key categories. These are supervised learning,
unsupervised learning, and semi supervised learning. So let's take a look at
supervised learning first. So, supervised learning can be broadly
broken out into two key categories. These are classification
and regression. Classification is all to do with grouping
things into categories or labels. So say you had a big data
set on all the different types of pizzas you've liked and whether or
not you've liked them. Yes or no. You could take that data and pass it
through to a classification algorithm to help it learn which types
of pizzas you like. So then when you pass through a new list of ingredients,
it would be able to predict, yes, you would like that pizza or no,
you might not. Regression, on the other hand, is all to do with
predicting continuous variables. Some great examples of regression are
sales forecasting and predicting prices of houses. So that encapsulates supervised
learning. Now, what about unsupervised learning? Well, there's two key things
to think about when you think of unsupervised learning.
These are really clustering. So the ability to group people together. So say you
wanted to group together high performing and low performing and medium
performing employees, or high value, low value, medium value
customers, or a whole bunch of other different types of data.
But really it's all to do with grouping things together. Now, dimensionality reduction,
on the other hand, is all to do with condensing the
features that you've got within a machine learning model. So a lot of the time
you might start out with a huge data set with a lot of columns,
and you're not really sure which of those columns are important for your machine learning
model. Dimensionality reduction helps you reduce the number of columns
that you've got so that you can really focus on the important ones.
Now, in order to remember supervised learning and unsupervised
learning, I'd suggest you remember this initialism,
Christopher Robin caught a duck. So that way you remember classification,
regression, clustering and dimensionality reduction.
So that takes care of supervised and unsupervised learning. But what about semi
supervised learning? Well, this is where reinforcement learning comes
in. Now, reinforcement learning has four key things. These are an
agent, an action, an environment, and a reward. It's similar to
how you might choose to condition a dog. A dog might do
something right and you might reward it with a piece of food.
In a similar way, we train reinforcement learning models to act
in a correct way in a given environment in order to learn appropriate
actions given that specific environment. Now, the best way to remember
reinforcement learning techniques is to remember area 51.
So that way you remember agent reward environment and actions.
Okay? So that takes care of machine learning. Now we're going to delve a little
bit deeper and get into deep learning. So deep learning
is a subset of machine learning, and really it's to do with performing machine
learning tasks using deep neural networks.
Now, deep neural networks are networks that have multiple hidden
layers. So if you've ever seen a diagram that looks sort of like
this, this is a representation of a neural network.
But specifically in this case, this is a deep neural network because
it has multiple hidden layers. Now, the best way to remember deep learning
is to remember that deep learning is just like an onion. It has multiple
layers, a little bit like Shrek. Now, that sort of covers AI,
ML and DL. What about data science? Well, data science
is the practice that sits over AI, ML and DL.
It basically is the art of extracting knowledge,
insight and meaning from data. The best way to remember the key components of data
science are to look at the CrispDM framework.
So the CrisPDM framework stands for the cross industry standard process
for data mining. And basically it's a framework to help you along your
way to producing really good data science projects. Now,
there's six key steps in the data science process.
These are business understanding. So understanding the business that
you're working with and the environment in which they operate. Two data
understanding. So understanding the data that you've got on hand. So whether
or not you've got missing values, visualizing that data and taking a
look at some summary statistics, we've then got data preparation.
So this is all to do with getting our data ready for modeling. In this
step, we might perform some feature engineering and create some new columns. We might
fill in some missing values and, and a whole bunch of other data preparation steps,
like, for example, splitting our data into training and testing.
Next, we've got my favorite, which is modeling. This is all to do with training
your machine learning algorithms to perform well on a specific
task. Once we've trained our models in that modeling step, we get onto
evaluation. Given that we've trained our model, we want to make sure that it's going
to work well once we deploy it into the real world. This is
what the evaluation step is all about. In this step, we try to check whether
or not our model is likely to perform well using specific evaluation metrics.
Now, once we've gone through all of that, the last step is to go and
deploy our model. In order to deploy our model, we could release it
as a rest API, containerize it up or save it as a binary
so we can go and use it elsewhere. Now, a great way to
remember CrispDM is to remember Barry drove directly to the medical
emergency department. That way you remember business understanding
data, understanding data preparation, modeling,
evaluation, and deployment. Now, I've talked a lot about theory, but where
do the python packages that you typically see used fit into
this framework? Well, in terms of data science, numpy,
pandas and Matplotlib are probably going to be the most important packages that you
see floating around. Numpy and pandas help you traverse
and explore your data and really work with your data. In terms of performing manipulations
and data preparation, Matplotlib and Seaborn help
you visualize that data and explore it even further. Now,
the most important library in terms of machine learning is probably scikit learn.
So scikit learn has been around for quite some time and gives you a whole
bunch of really powerful algorithms and utilities to help
use them to train your machine learning models. Now, deep learning is becoming
increasingly popular, and there's a large number of libraries that can help you
perform deep learning, some of which, which are notable, are tensorflow,
Keras, Pytorch, and piano, just to name a few.
And that about wraps up AI versus ML versus DL
versus ds. Thanks so much for tuning in, guys. Hopefully you found
this video useful. If you did, be sure to give it a thumbs up and
hit subscribe until next time.
Ever wondered about the differences between AI, ML, DL and
ds? Well, we're about to explore all of those today. Stay tuned.
So let's dive right into it. So AI versus ML versus DL versus
DS, a whole bunch of jargon, but we're going to clarify all of that
right up. So let's kick things off and take a look at AI.
So AI is really to do with the ability of computers
and machines to perform tasks without explicitly programming
them, otherwise known as the ability for computers and machines to
think by themselves. So we typically break out AI
into two key categories. These are general AI and narrow AI.
General AI typically refers to the ability for a computer or a
machine to be able to handle a wide variety of tasks.
Us as humans have the ability to do a whole heap of stuff. We can
see, we can speak, we can hear, we can read, we can drive, we can
do a whole range of things. The ability for AI and
machines to be able to do a broad range of tasks similar to humans is
what we typically refer to as general AI. Now,
we're still a little bit of a while away from true general AI,
but that's not to say it's not to come. Now,
narrow AI, on the other hand, is the ability for a machine to
handle a really simple or a really narrow range of tasks.
So that could possibly be the ability to translate speech to text,
or to classify images as having different categories, or the ability
to predict house prices, for example, or all of these are examples of narrow
AI. So I'm going to be painting a bunch of visual imagery to
help you remember some of these topics. So the first one, in terms of breaking
out general and narrow AI, or the ability to remember general and narrow AI,
is just picture a really narrow or really skinny general in
your mind. So that way you know that there's two different types of AI,
general and narrow. Now onto the next topic, machine learning. So we've
taken a look at AI as being broken up into general and narrow. But how
does machine learning fit into this? Well, machine learning is the application
of narrow AI to specific tasks. Now, when we typically talk
about machine learning, we often compare it to traditional programming. So in traditional
programming, we supply data plus rules or conditional logic,
and we get answers. Now, in machine learning, on the other hand,
we provide data plus historical answers to get rules.
We can then pass new data to get new answers. So this is a bit
of a change in the paradigm of how computer scientists and machine learning
engineers are building programs these days. So what are some typical
machine learning tasks? Well, we broadly break out machine learning
into three key categories. These are supervised learning,
unsupervised learning, and semi supervised learning. So let's take a look at
supervised learning first. So, supervised learning can be broadly broken out
into two key categories. These are classification and regression.
Classification is all to do with grouping things into categories
or labels. So say you had a big data set on all the different
types of pizzas you've liked and whether or not you've liked them. Yes or no.
You could take that data and pass it through to a classification algorithm to
help it learn which types of pizzas you like. So then when you pass through
a new list of ingredients, it would be able to predict, yes, you would like
that pizza or no, you might not. Regression, on the other hand,
is all to do with predicting continuous variables. Some great examples of
regression are sales forecasting and predicting prices of houses.
So that encapsulates supervised learning. Now, what about unsupervised learning?
Well, there's two key things to think about when you think of unsupervised
learning. These are really clustering. So the ability to group people together.
So say you wanted to group together high performing and low performing and
medium performing employees, or high value, low value,
medium value customers, or a whole bunch of other different types of data.
But really it's all to do with grouping things together. Now,
dimensionality reduction, on the other hand, is all to do with condensing
the features that you've got within a machine learning model. So a lot of
the time you might start out with a huge data set with a lot of
columns, and you're not really sure which of those columns are important for
your machine learning model. Dimensionality reduction helps you reduce the
number of columns that you've got so that you can really focus on the important
ones. Now, in order to remember supervised learning and unsupervised
learning, I'd suggest you remember this initialism,
Christopher Robin caught a duck. So that way you remember classification,
regression, clustering and dimensionality reduction.
So that takes care of supervised and unsupervised learning. But what about semi
supervised learning? Well, this is where reinforcement learning comes in.
Now, reinforcement learning has four key things. These are
an agent, an action, an environment, and a reward.
It's similar to how you might choose to condition a dog.
A dog might do something right and you might reward it with a piece of
food. In a similar way, we train reinforcement learning models
to act in a correct way in a given environment in order to learn
appropriate actions given that specific environment. Now,
the best way to remember reinforcement learning techniques is to remember area
51. So that way you remember agent reward environment and actions.
Okay? So that takes care of machine learning. Now we're going to delve a little
bit deeper and get into deep learning. So deep learning
is a subset of machine learning, and really it's to do with performing machine
learning tasks using deep neural networks.
Now, deep neural networks are networks that have multiple hidden layers.
So if you've ever seen a diagram that looks sort of like this,
this is a representation of a neural network.
But specifically in this case, this is a deep neural network because it
has multiple hidden layers. Now, the best way to remember deep
learning is to remember that deep learning is just like an onion.
It has multiple layers, a little bit like Shrek. Now, that sort of covers
AI, ML and DL. What about data science?
Well, data science is the practice that sits over AI,
ML and DL. It basically is the art of extracting
knowledge, insight and meaning from data. The best way to remember
the key components of data science are to look at the CrispDM
framework. So the CrisPDM framework stands for the cross industry
standard process for data mining. And basically it's a framework to help
you along your way to producing really good data science projects.
Now, there's six key steps in the data science process.
These are business understanding. So understanding the business that you're
working with and the environment in which they operate.
Two data understanding. So understanding the data that you've got
on hand. So whether or not you've got missing values, visualizing that data
and taking a look at some summary statistics, we've then got data preparation.
So this is all to do with getting our data ready for modeling. In this
step, we might perform some feature engineering and create some new columns. We might
fill in some missing values and, and a whole bunch of other data preparation
steps, like, for example, splitting our data into training and testing.
Next, we've got my favorite, which is modeling. This is all to do with training
your machine learning algorithms to perform well on a specific
task. Once we've trained our models in that modeling step,
we get onto evaluation. Given that we've trained our model, we want to
make sure that it's going to work well once we deploy it into the real
world. This is what the evaluation step is all about. In this
step, we try to check whether or not our model is likely to perform well
using specific evaluation metrics. Now, once we've gone through
all of that, the last step is to go and deploy our model.
In order to deploy our model, we could release it as a rest API,
containerize it up or save it as a binary so we can go and use
it elsewhere. Now, a great way to remember CrispDM is to remember Barry
drove directly to the medical emergency department.
That way you remember business understanding data, understanding data preparation,
modeling, evaluation, and deployment. Now, I've talked a lot
about theory, but where do the python packages that you typically see
used fit into this framework? Well, in terms of data science,
numpy, pandas and Matplotlib are probably going to be the most important packages
that you see floating around. Numpy and pandas help you traverse
and explore your data and really work with your data. In terms of performing
manipulations and data preparation,
Matplotlib and Seaborn help you visualize that data and explore
it even further. Now, the most important library in terms of machine learning
is probably scikit learn. So scikit learn has been around for quite some
time and gives you a whole bunch of really powerful algorithms
and utilities to help use them to train your machine learning models.
Now, deep learning is becoming increasingly popular, and there's a
large number of libraries that can help you perform deep learning,
some of which, which are notable, are tensorflow, Keras,
Pytorch, and piano, just to name a few. And that about wraps
up AI versus ML versus DL versus ds.
Thanks so much for tuning in, guys. Hopefully you found this video useful.
If you did, be sure to give it a thumbs up and hit subscribe until
next time.