Ever wondered about the differences between AI, ML, DL and
ds? Well, we're about to explore all of those today. Stay tuned.
So let's dive right into it. So AI versus ML versus DL
versus DS, a whole bunch of jargon, but we're going to clarify
all of that right up. So let's kick things off and take a look
at AI. So AI is really to
do with the ability of computers and machines to perform
tasks without explicitly programming them,
otherwise known as the ability for computers and machines to think by
themselves. So we typically break out AI into two key categories.
These are general AI and narrow AI.
General AI typically refers to the ability for a computer or a
machine to be able to handle a wide variety of tasks.
Us as humans have the ability to do a whole heap of stuff. We can
see, we can speak, we can hear, we can read, we can drive, we can
do a whole range of things. The ability for AI and
machines to be able to do a broad range of tasks similar to humans is
what we typically refer to as general AI.
Now, we're still a little bit of a while away from true general AI,
but that's not to say it's not to come. Now, narrow AI,
on the other hand, is the ability for a machine to handle a really simple
or a really narrow range of tasks. So that could possibly be the
ability to translate speech to text, or to classify images as
having different categories, or the ability to predict house prices,
for example. All of these are examples of narrow AI.
So I'm going to be painting a bunch of visual imagery to help you remember
some of these topics. So the first one, in terms of breaking out general and
narrow AI, or the ability to remember general and narrow AI,
is just picture a really narrow or really skinny general in your
mind. So that way you know that there's two different types of AI,
general and narrow. Now onto the next topic, machine learning. So we've
taken a look at AI as being broken up into general and narrow. But how
does machine learning fit into this? Well, machine learning
is the application of narrow AI to specific tasks.
Now, when we typically talk about machine learning, we often compare it to traditional programming.
So in traditional programming, we supply data plus rules or conditional
logic, and we get answers. Now, in machine learning, on the other hand,
we provide data plus historical answers to get rules. We can
then pass new data to get new answers. So this is a bit of a
change in the paradigm of how computer scientists and machine learning
engineers are building programs these days. So what are some typical
machine learning tasks? Well, we broadly break out machine learning
into three key categories. These are supervised learning,
unsupervised learning, and semisupervised learning. So let's take a look at
supervised learning first. So, supervised learning can be broadly
broken out into two key categories. These are classification and
regression. Classification is all to do with grouping
things into categories or labels. So say you had a big data
set on all the different types of pizzas you've liked and whether
or not you've liked them. Yes or no, you could take that data and
pass it through to a classification algorithm to help it learn
which types of pizzas you like. So then when you pass through a new list
of ingredients, it would be able to predict, yes, you would like that pizza or
no, you might not. Regression, on the other hand, is all to do with
predicting continuous variables. Some great examples of regression are
sales forecasting and predicting prices of houses. So that encapsulates supervised
learning. Now, what about unsupervised learning? Well, there's two
key things to think about when you think of unsupervised learning.
These are really clustering. So the ability to group people together.
So say you wanted to group together high performing and low performing and
medium performing employees, or high value, low value, medium value
customers, or a whole bunch of other different types of data.
But really it's all to do with grouping things together. Now,
dimensionality reduction, on the other hand, is all to do with condensing
the features that you've got within a machine learning model. So a lot of
the time you might start out with a huge data set with a lot of
columns, and you're not really sure which of those columns are important for your machine
learning model, dimensionality reduction helps you reduce the number of
columns that you've got so that you can really focus on the important ones.
Now, in order to remember supervised learning and unsupervised
learning, I'd suggest you remember this initialism,
Christopher Robin caught a duck. So that way you remember classification,
regression, clustering and dimensionality reduction. So that
takes care of supervised and unsupervised learning. But what about semi supervised
learning? Well, this is where reinforcement learning comes in.
Now, reinforcement learning has four key things. These are
an agent, an action, an environment, and a reward.
It's similar to how you might choose to condition a dog.
A dog might do something right, and you might reward it with a
piece of food. In a similar way, we train reinforcement learning models
to act in a correct way in a given environment in order to learn
appropriate actions given that specific environment. Now, the best way
to remember, reinforcement learning techniques is to remember area
51. So that way you remember agent reward environment and actions.
Okay? So that takes care of machine learning. Now we're going to delve a little
bit deeper and get into deep learning. So deep learning is a
subset of machine learning, and really it's to do with performing machine
learning tasks using deep neural networks.
Now, deep neural networks are networks that have multiple hidden layers.
So if you've ever seen a diagram that looks sort of like this, this is
a representation of a neural network.
But specifically in this case, this is a deep neural network because
it has multiple hidden layers. Now, the best way to
remember deep learning is to remember that deep learning is just like an
onion. It has multiple layers, little bit like Shrek. Now, that sort
of covers AI, ML and DL. What about data science?
Well, data science is the practice that sits over AI,
ML and DL. It basically is the art of extracting
knowledge, insight and meaning from data. The best way to remember the key
components of data science are to look at the crisp DM
framework. So the crisp DM framework stands for the cross industry
standard process for data mining. And basically it's a framework to
help you along your way to producing really good data science projects.
Now, there's six key steps in the data science process.
These are business understanding. So understanding the business that you're working
with and the environment in which they operate. Two data understanding.
So understanding the data that you've got on hand. So whether or not you've
got missing values, visualizing that data and taking a look at some summary
statistics, we've then got data preparation. So this is all
to do with getting our data ready for modeling. In this step, we might
perform some feature engineering and create some new columns. We might fill
in some missing values and a whole bunch of other data preparation
steps, like, for example, splitting our data into training and testing.
Next, we've got my favorite, which is modeling. This is all to do with training
your machine learning algorithms to perform well on a specific
task. Once we've trained our models in that modeling step,
we get onto evaluation. Given that we've trained our model, we want
to make sure that it's going to work well once we deploy it into the
real world. This is what the evaluation step is all about.
In this step, we try to check whether or not our model is likely to
perform well using specific evaluation metrics. Now, once we've gone
through all of that, the last step is to go and deploy our model.
In order to deploy our model, we could release it as a rest API containerize
it up or save it as a binary so we can go and use it
elsewhere. Now, a great way to remember Chris DM is to
remember Barry drove directly to the medical emergency department.
That way you remember business understanding data understanding data
preparation, modeling, evaluation, and deployment.
Now, I've talked a lot about theory, but where do the python packages that you
typically see used fit into this framework? Well, in terms of
data science, numpy, pandas, and Matplotlib are probably going to be the most
important packages that you see floating around. Numpy and pandas
help you traverse and explore your data and really work with your data
in terms of performing manipulations and data preparation.
Matplotlib and Seaborne help you visualize that data and explore
it even further. Now, the most important library in terms of machine learning
is probably scikitlearn. So Scikitlearn's been around for quite some
time and gives you a whole bunch of really powerful
algorithms and utilities to help use them to train your machine
learning models. Now, deep learning is becoming increasingly popular,
and there's a large number of libraries that can help you perform
deep learning. Some of which are notable are tensorflow,
Keras, Pytorch, and piano, just to name a few. And that
about wraps up AI versus ML versus DL vs.
Ds. Thanks so much for tuning in, guys. Hopefully you found this video
useful. If you did, be sure to give it a thumbs up and hit subscribe.
Until next time.
Ever wondered about the differences between AI, ML,
DL and ds? Well, we're about to explore all of those today.
Stay tuned. So let's dive right into it. So AI versus ML
versus DL versus DS, a whole bunch of jargon, but we're going to clarify
all of that right up. So let's kick things off and take a look at
AI. So AI is really
to do with the ability of computers and machines to perform tasks without
explicitly programming them, otherwise known as the ability for
computers and machines to think by themselves. So we typically
break out AI into two key categories. These are general
AI and narrow AI. General AI typically refers
to the ability for a computer or a machine to be able to handle a
wide variety of tasks. Us as humans have the
ability to do a whole heap of stuff. We can see, we can speak,
we can hear, we can read, we can drive, we can do a whole range
of things. The ability for AI and machines to be able
to do a broad range of tasks similar to humans is what we typically
refer to as general AI. Now, we're still
a little bit of a while away from true general AI, but that's not to
say it's not to come. Now, narrow AI,
on the other hand, is the ability for a machine to handle a really simple
or a really narrow range of tasks. So that could possibly be the
ability to translate speech to text, or to classify images as
having different categories, or the ability to predict house prices,
for example. All of these are examples of narrow AI.
So I'm going to be painting a bunch of visual imagery to help you
remember some of these topics. So the first one, in terms of breaking out general
and narrow AI, or the ability to remember general and narrow AI,
is just picture a really narrow or really skinny general in your mind.
So that way you know that there's two different types of AI, general and
narrow. Now onto the next topic, machine learning. So we've taken a look at AI
as being broken up into general and narrow. But how does machine learning fit into
this? Well, machine learning is the application of narrow
AI to specific tasks. Now, when we typically talk
about machine learning, we often compare it to traditional programming. So in traditional
programming, we supply data plus rules or conditional logic,
and we get answers. Now, in machine learning, on the other hand,
we provide data plus historical answers to get rules.
We can then pass new data to get new answers. So this is a
bit of a change in the paradigm of how computer scientists and machine learning engineers
are building programs these days. So what are some typical machine
learning tasks? Well, we broadly break out machine learning into
three key categories. These are supervised learning,
unsupervised learning, and semisupervised learning. So let's take a look at
supervised learning first. So, supervised learning can be broadly broken out into
two key categories. These are classification and regression.
Classification is all to do with grouping things into
categories or labels. So say you had a big data set on all
the different types of pizzas you've liked and whether or not you've liked them.
Yes or no, you could take that data and pass it through to a
classification algorithm to help it learn which types of pizzas you like.
So then when you pass through a new list of ingredients, it would be able
to predict, yes, you would like that pizza or no, you might not.
Regression, on the other hand, is all to do with predicting continuous variables.
Some great examples of regression are sales forecasting and predicting prices
of houses. So that encapsulates supervised learning. Now, what about unsupervised
learning? Well, there's two key things to think about when you think of
unsupervised learning. These are really clustering. So the ability to group
people together. So say you wanted to group together high performing and low performing and
medium performing employees, or high value, low value,
medium value customers, or a whole bunch of other different types of data.
But really it's all to do with grouping things together. Now,
dimensionality reduction, on the other hand, is all to do with condensing
the features that you've got within a machine learning model. So a lot
of the time you might start out with a huge data set with a lot
of columns, and you're not really sure which of those columns are important for
your machine learning model, dimensionality reduction helps you reduce
the number of columns that you've got so that you can really focus
on the important ones. Now, in order to remember
supervised learning and unsupervised learning, I'd suggest you remember
this initialism, Christopher Robin caught a duck. So that way
you remember classification, regression, clustering and dimensionality
reduction. So that takes care of supervised and unsupervised learning.
But what about semi supervised learning? Well, this is where reinforcement
learning comes in. Now, reinforcement learning has four key
things. These are an agent, an action, an environment,
and a reward. It's similar to how you might choose to condition a
dog. A dog might do something right, and you might reward it with a
piece of food. In a similar way, we train reinforcement learning models
to act in a correct way in a given environment in order
to learn appropriate actions given that specific environment.
Now, the best way to remember, reinforcement learning techniques is to remember
area 51. So that way you remember agent reward environment
and actions. Okay? So that takes care of machine learning. Now we're going to
delve a little bit deeper and get into deep learning. So deep learning
is a subset of machine learning, and really it's to do with performing
machine learning tasks using deep neural networks.
Now, deep neural networks are networks that have multiple hidden layers.
So if you've ever seen a diagram that looks sort of like this,
this is a representation of a neural network.
But specifically in this case, this is a deep neural network because
it has multiple hidden layers. Now, the best way to remember
deep learning is to remember that deep learning is just like an onion.
It has multiple layers, little bit like Shrek. Now,
that sort of covers AI, ML and DL. What about data
science? Well, data science is the practice that sits over
AI, ML and DL. It basically is the art
of extracting knowledge, insight and meaning from data.
The best way to remember the key components of data science are to look at
the crisp DM framework. So the crisp DM framework stands
for the cross industry standard process for data mining. And basically it's
a framework to help you along your way to producing really good
data science projects. Now, there's six key steps in the
data science process. These are business understanding. So understanding
the business that you're working with and the environment in which they operate.
Two data understanding. So understanding the data that you've
got on hand. So whether or not you've got missing values, visualizing that data
and taking a look at some summary statistics, we've then got data preparation.
So this is all to do with getting our data ready for modeling.
In this step, we might perform some feature engineering and create some new columns.
We might fill in some missing values and a whole bunch of other data preparation
steps, like, for example, splitting our data into training and
testing. Next, we've got my favorite, which is modeling. This is all
to do with training your machine learning algorithms to perform
well on a specific task. Once we've trained our models
in that modeling step, we get onto evaluation. Given that we've
trained our model, we want to make sure that it's going to work well once
we deploy it into the real world. This is what the evaluation step
is all about. In this step, we try to check whether or not our
model is likely to perform well using specific evaluation
metrics. Now, once we've gone through all of that, the last step is to
go and deploy our model. In order to deploy our model, we could release it
as a rest API containerize it up or save it as a binary
so we can go and use it elsewhere. Now, a great way
to remember Chris DM is to remember Barry drove directly
to the medical emergency department. That way you remember business understanding
data understanding data preparation, modeling,
evaluation, and deployment. Now, I've talked a lot about theory, but where do the
python packages that you typically see used fit into this
framework? Well, in terms of data science, numpy,
pandas, and Matplotlib are probably going to be the most important packages that you see
floating around. Numpy and pandas help you traverse and
explore your data and really work with your data in terms of performing manipulations
and data preparation. Matplotlib and Seaborne help you
visualize that data and explore it even further.
Now, the most important library in terms of machine learning is probably scikitlearn.
So Scikitlearn's been around for quite some time and gives you a
whole bunch of really powerful algorithms and utilities to
help use them to train your machine learning models. Now, deep learning is becoming
increasingly popular, and there's a large number of libraries that can help
you perform deep learning. Some of which are notable are
tensorflow, Keras, Pytorch, and piano, just to
name a few. And that about wraps up AI versus ML
versus DL vs. Ds. Thanks so much for tuning in, guys.
Hopefully you found this video useful. If you did, be sure to give it a
thumbs up and hit subscribe. Until next time.
Ever wondered about the differences between AI, ML, DL and
ds? Well, we're about to explore all of those today. Stay tuned.
So let's dive right into it. So AI versus ML versus
DL versus DS, a whole bunch of jargon, but we're going to clarify
all of that right up. So let's kick things off and take a look at
AI. So AI is really to
do with the ability of computers and machines to perform tasks without
explicitly programming them, otherwise known as the
ability for computers and machines to think by themselves.
So we typically break out AI into two key categories. These are
general AI and narrow AI. General AI typically
refers to the ability for a computer or a machine to be able to handle
a wide variety of tasks. Us as humans
have the ability to do a whole heap of stuff. We can see, we can
speak, we can hear, we can read, we can drive, we can do a whole
range of things. The ability for AI and machines
to be able to do a broad range of tasks similar to humans is what
we typically refer to as general AI. Now,
we're still a little bit of a while away from true general AI,
but that's not to say it's not to come. Now, narrow AI,
on the other hand, is the ability for a machine to handle a really simple
or a really narrow range of tasks. So that could possibly be the
ability to translate speech to text, or to classify images as
having different categories, or the ability to predict house prices,
for example. All of these are examples of narrow AI.
So I'm going to be painting a bunch of visual imagery to help you remember
some of these topics. So the first one, in terms of breaking out general and
narrow AI, or the ability to remember general and narrow AI,
is just picture a really narrow or really skinny general in
your mind. So that way you know that there's two different types of AI,
general and narrow. Now onto the next topic, machine learning. So we've taken a
look at AI as being broken up into general and narrow. But how does machine
learning fit into this? Well, machine learning is the application
of narrow AI to specific tasks. Now, when we typically
talk about machine learning, we often compare it to traditional programming. So in
traditional programming, we supply data plus rules or conditional logic,
and we get answers. Now, in machine learning, on the other hand, we provide data
plus historical answers to get rules. We can then pass new
data to get new answers. So this is a bit of a change in the
paradigm of how computer scientists and machine learning engineers are
building programs these days. So what are some typical machine learning
tasks? Well, we broadly break out machine learning
into three key categories. These are supervised learning,
unsupervised learning, and semisupervised learning. So let's take a look at supervised
learning first. So, supervised learning can be broadly broken out into
two key categories. These are classification and regression.
Classification is all to do with grouping things into categories
or labels. So say you had a big data set on all the different types
of pizzas you've liked and whether or not you've liked them. Yes or no,
you could take that data and pass it through to a classification algorithm
to help it learn which types of pizzas you like. So then when you pass
through a new list of ingredients, it would be able to predict, yes,
you would like that pizza or no, you might not. Regression,
on the other hand, is all to do with predicting continuous variables.
Some great examples of regression are sales forecasting and
predicting prices of houses. So that encapsulates supervised learning.
Now, what about unsupervised learning? Well, there's two key things to
think about when you think of unsupervised learning. These are really clustering.
So the ability to group people together. So say you wanted to group together
high performing and low performing and medium performing employees,
or high value, low value, medium value customers, or a whole bunch
of other different types of data. But really it's all to do with grouping
things together. Now, dimensionality reduction, on the other hand, is all to
do with condensing the features that you've got within a machine
learning model. So a lot of the time you might start out with a huge
data set with a lot of columns, and you're not really sure which of those
columns are important for your machine learning model, dimensionality reduction
helps you reduce the number of columns that you've got so that you can really
focus on the important ones. Now, in order to remember supervised
learning and unsupervised learning, I'd suggest you remember this
initialism, Christopher Robin caught a duck. So that way you
remember classification, regression, clustering and dimensionality
reduction. So that takes care of supervised and unsupervised learning.
But what about semi supervised learning? Well, this is where reinforcement
learning comes in. Now, reinforcement learning has four key things.
These are an agent, an action, an environment, and a
reward. It's similar to how you might choose to condition a
dog. A dog might do something right, and you might reward it with a piece
of food. In a similar way, we train reinforcement learning models
to act in a correct way in a given environment in order to
learn appropriate actions given that specific environment.
Now, the best way to remember, reinforcement learning techniques is to remember
area 51. So that way you remember agent reward
environment and actions. Okay? So that takes care of machine
learning. Now we're going to delve a little bit deeper and get into deep learning.
So deep learning is a subset of machine learning, and really it's
to do with performing machine learning tasks using deep
neural networks. Now, deep neural networks are networks that have
multiple hidden layers. So if you've ever seen a diagram that
looks sort of like this, this is a representation of a
neural network. But specifically in this case, this is a
deep neural network because it has multiple hidden layers. Now,
the best way to remember deep learning is to remember that deep learning is just
like an onion. It has multiple layers, little bit like Shrek.
Now, that sort of covers AI, ML and DL. What about
data science? Well, data science is the practice that sits
over AI, ML and DL. It basically is the
art of extracting knowledge, insight and meaning from data.
The best way to remember the key components of data science are to look at
the crisp DM framework. So the crisp DM framework stands
for the cross industry standard process for data mining. And basically it's a
framework to help you along your way to producing really good data
science projects. Now, there's six key steps in the data
science process. These are business understanding. So understanding
the business that you're working with and the environment in which they operate.
Two data understanding. So understanding the data that you've
got on hand. So whether or not you've got missing values, visualizing that
data and taking a look at some summary statistics, we've then
got data preparation. So this is all to do with getting our data
ready for modeling. In this step, we might perform some feature engineering
and create some new columns. We might fill in some missing values and a whole
bunch of other data preparation steps, like, for example, splitting our
data into training and testing. Next, we've got my
favorite, which is modeling. This is all to do with training your machine learning algorithms
to perform well on a specific task.
Once we've trained our models in that modeling step, we get onto evaluation.
Given that we've trained our model, we want to make sure that it's going to
work well once we deploy it into the real world. This is what the
evaluation step is all about. In this step, we try to
check whether or not our model is likely to perform well using specific evaluation
metrics. Now, once we've gone through all of that, the last step is
to go and deploy our model. In order to deploy our model, we could release
it as a rest API containerize it up or save it as a binary
so we can go and use it elsewhere. Now, a great way to remember
Chris DM is to remember Barry drove directly to the medical emergency
department. That way you remember business understanding data
understanding data preparation, modeling, evaluation,
and deployment. Now, I've talked a lot about theory, but where do the python packages
that you typically see used fit into this framework? Well,
in terms of data science, numpy, pandas, and Matplotlib are probably going to
be the most important packages that you see floating around.
Numpy and pandas help you traverse and explore your
data and really work with your data in terms of performing manipulations
and data preparation. Matplotlib and Seaborne help you visualize
that data and explore it even further. Now, the most important
library in terms of machine learning is probably scikitlearn. So Scikitlearn's
been around for quite some time and gives you a whole bunch of
really powerful algorithms and utilities to help use them to
train your machine learning models. Now, deep learning is becoming
increasingly popular, and there's a large number of libraries that can
help you perform deep learning. Some of which are notable
are tensorflow, Keras, Pytorch, and piano,
just to name a few. And that about wraps up AI versus ML versus
DL vs. Ds. Thanks so much for tuning in, guys.
Hopefully you found this video useful. If you did, be sure to give it a
thumbs up and hit subscribe. Until next time.
Ever wondered about the differences between AI, ML, DL and ds?
Well, we're about to explore all of those today. Stay tuned. So let's
dive right into it. So AI versus ML versus DL versus
DS, a whole bunch of jargon, but we're going to clarify all of
that right up. So let's kick things off and take a look at AI.
So AI is really to do with the ability of computers
and machines to perform tasks without explicitly programming them,
otherwise known as the ability for computers and machines to
think by themselves. So we typically break out AI into
two key categories. These are general AI and narrow AI.
General AI typically refers to the ability for a computer
or a machine to be able to handle a wide variety of tasks.
Us as humans have the ability to do a whole heap of stuff. We can
see, we can speak, we can hear, we can read, we can drive,
we can do a whole range of things. The ability for AI and machines
to be able to do a broad range of tasks similar to humans is what
we typically refer to as general AI.
Now, we're still a little bit of a while away from true general AI,
but that's not to say it's not to come. Now, narrow AI,
on the other hand, is the ability for a machine to handle a really simple
or a really narrow range of tasks. So that could possibly be the ability
to translate speech to text, or to classify images as having
different categories, or the ability to predict house prices, for example.
All of these are examples of narrow AI. So I'm going to be
painting a bunch of visual imagery to help you remember some of these topics.
So the first one, in terms of breaking out general and narrow AI,
or the ability to remember general and narrow AI, is just picture a
really narrow or really skinny general in your mind. So that way you know that
there's two different types of AI, general and narrow.
Now onto the next topic, machine learning. So we've taken a look at AI as
being broken up into general and narrow. But how does machine learning fit into
this? Well, machine learning is the application of narrow
AI to specific tasks. Now, when we typically talk about machine learning,
we often compare it to traditional programming. So in traditional programming,
we supply data plus rules or conditional logic,
and we get answers. Now, in machine learning, on the other hand,
we provide data plus historical answers to get rules. We can
then pass new data to get new answers. So this is a bit of a
change in the paradigm of how computer scientists and machine learning engineers are
building programs these days. So what are some typical machine learning tasks?
Well, we broadly break out machine learning into three key
categories. These are supervised learning,
unsupervised learning, and semisupervised learning. So let's take a look at supervised learning
first. So, supervised learning can be broadly broken out into two
key categories. These are classification and regression.
Classification is all to do with grouping things into categories
or labels. So say you had a big data set on all the different types
of pizzas you've liked and whether or not you've liked them. Yes or no,
you could take that data and pass it through to a classification algorithm
to help it learn which types of pizzas you like. So then when you pass
through a new list of ingredients, it would be able to predict, yes, you would
like that pizza or no, you might not. Regression, on the other hand,
is all to do with predicting continuous variables. Some great examples
of regression are sales forecasting and predicting prices of houses.
So that encapsulates supervised learning. Now, what about unsupervised learning?
Well, there's two key things to think about when you think of unsupervised
learning. These are really clustering. So the ability to group
people together. So say you wanted to group together high performing and low performing
and medium performing employees, or high value, low value,
medium value customers, or a whole bunch of other different types of data.
But really it's all to do with grouping things together. Now, dimensionality reduction,
on the other hand, is all to do with condensing the
features that you've got within a machine learning model. So a lot of the time
you might start out with a huge data set with a lot of columns,
and you're not really sure which of those columns are important for your machine learning
model, dimensionality reduction helps you reduce the number of columns
that you've got so that you can really focus on the important ones.
Now, in order to remember supervised learning and unsupervised learning,
I'd suggest you remember this initialism, Christopher Robin caught
a duck. So that way you remember classification, regression,
clustering and dimensionality reduction. So that takes care of
supervised and unsupervised learning. But what about semi supervised learning?
Well, this is where reinforcement learning comes in. Now,
reinforcement learning has four key things. These are an
agent, an action, an environment, and a reward. It's similar to
how you might choose to condition a dog. A dog might do something right,
and you might reward it with a piece of food. In a similar
way, we train reinforcement learning models to act in a correct
way in a given environment in order to learn appropriate actions
given that specific environment. Now, the best way to remember,
reinforcement learning techniques is to remember area 51.
So that way you remember agent reward environment and actions.
Okay? So that takes care of machine learning. Now we're going to delve a little
bit deeper and get into deep learning. So deep learning is a subset
of machine learning, and really it's to do with performing machine learning
tasks using deep neural networks.
Now, deep neural networks are networks that have multiple hidden layers.
So if you've ever seen a diagram that looks sort of like this,
this is a representation of a neural network.
But specifically in this case, this is a deep neural network
because it has multiple hidden layers. Now, the best way to remember
deep learning is to remember that deep learning is just like an onion. It has
multiple layers, little bit like Shrek. Now, that sort of
covers AI, ML and DL. What about data science?
Well, data science is the practice that sits over AI,
ML and DL. It basically is the art of extracting
knowledge, insight and meaning from data. The best way to remember the
key components of data science are to look at the crisp DM framework.
So the crisp DM framework stands for the cross industry standard process
for data mining. And basically it's a framework to help you along
your way to producing really good data science projects. Now,
there's six key steps in the data science process.
These are business understanding. So understanding the business that
you're working with and the environment in which they operate.
Two data understanding. So understanding the data that you've got
on hand. So whether or not you've got missing values, visualizing that data
and taking a look at some summary statistics, we've then got data preparation.
So this is all to do with getting our data ready for modeling. In this
step, we might perform some feature engineering and create some new columns. We might
fill in some missing values and a whole bunch of other data preparation
steps, like, for example, splitting our data into training and testing.
Next, we've got my favorite, which is modeling. This is all to do with
training your machine learning algorithms to perform well on a specific
task. Once we've trained our models in that modeling step,
we get onto evaluation. Given that we've trained our model,
we want to make sure that it's going to work well once we deploy it
into the real world. This is what the evaluation step is all about.
In this step, we try to check whether or not our model is likely to
perform well using specific evaluation metrics. Now, once we've
gone through all of that, the last step is to go and deploy our model.
In order to deploy our model, we could release it as a rest API containerize
it up or save it as a binary so we can go and use it
elsewhere. Now, a great way to remember Chris DM is to remember
Barry drove directly to the medical emergency department. That way
you remember business understanding data understanding data
preparation, modeling, evaluation, and deployment. Now, I've talked
a lot about theory, but where do the python packages that you typically see used
fit into this framework? Well, in terms of data science,
numpy, pandas, and Matplotlib are probably going to be the most important
packages that you see floating around. Numpy and pandas help you
traverse and explore your data and really work with your data in
terms of performing manipulations and data preparation.
Matplotlib and Seaborne help you visualize that data and explore
it even further. Now, the most important library in terms of machine learning
is probably scikitlearn. So Scikitlearn's been around for quite some
time and gives you a whole bunch of really powerful
algorithms and utilities to help use them to train your machine
learning models. Now, deep learning is becoming increasingly popular,
and there's a large number of libraries that can help you perform deep
learning. Some of which are notable are tensorflow,
Keras, Pytorch, and piano, just to name a few.
And that about wraps up AI versus ML versus DL vs.
Ds. Thanks so much for tuning in, guys. Hopefully you found this video
useful. If you did, be sure to give it a thumbs up and hit subscribe.
Until next time.